Guide to the Brian R. McNaught papers, circa 1970-2004
McNaught, Brian R. papers, circa 1970-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Brian R. McNaught papers, circa 1970-2004
7590
Brian R. McNaught
21.6 cubic feet
Correspondence, subject files, newspaper clippings, resumes, manuscripts, notes, reports, pamphlets, journals, books, ephemera, audiotapes, videotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Brian R. McNaught collection documents McNaught's career as a sexuality activist, a church activist, writer, and sensitivity trainer. Topics include the controversy of gays in the Catholic Church, AIDS training and awareness, homophobia in the workplace, and gay rights. McNaught's works, books and videos include A Disturbed Peace, On Being Gay, Gay Issues in the Workplace, Growing Up Gay and Lesbian, Homophobia in the Workplace, and Now That I'm Out, What Do I Do?.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Brian McNaught was born January 28, 1948 in Detroit, Michigan. He was educated in the Catholic schools, and at Marquette University, from which he graduated in 1970 with a degree in journalism.
McNaught's varied political and social activism includes his being a conscientious objector during the Vietnam War, protesting discrimination in the Catholic Church by going on a three week hunger strike, and serving as a spokesperson for gay and lesbian rights, especially as they pertain to the Catholic Church.
He has had careers as a newspaper columnist, writer, political appointee, gay activist, sexuality and AIDS educator, and corporate sensitivity trainer. McNaught has given numerous lectures and workshops at universities and corporations to help people gain a better understanding of gay and lesbian issues in the academic environment and the workplace.
McNaught served for two years, 1982-1984, as Boston Mayor Kevin White's liaison to the gay and lesbian community, the first full-time position of its kind. During this time, he worked with the mayor to write and implement the Boston Project, whose goal was to improve life for the city's gay and lesbian citizens. The project invited gay people to testify before city panels about how they were being treated. McNaught also established the first city government task force on AIDS in Boston in 1983.
As a newspaper columnist, McNaught wrote for several gay and Catholic publications, including the Michigan Catholic, the Blade, the Metro Gay Times, and Alive! magazine, as well as writing guest columns for several other publications. McNaught has also written books and produced videos. He has published On Being Gay, both as a book and video, and A Disturbed Peace, Gay Issues in the Workplace, Growing up Gay and Lesbian, Homophobia in the Workplace, and Now that I'm Out, What do I do?
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, subject files, newspaper clippings, resumes, manuscripts, notes, audiocassettes and videocassettes and other material documenting McNaught's career as a sexuality activist, a church activist, writer, and sensitivity trainer. Topics include the controversy of gays in the Catholic Church, AIDS training and awareness, homophobia in the workplace, and gay rights. Includes numerous letters from appreciators and detractors of McNaught's work, newspaper articles about McNaught, and copies of his books and video programs. Also includes a daily diary kept during a hunger strike and civil rights battle with the Catholic Church in Detroit, 1974. In addition to the Catholic Church, organizations figuring prominently in the collection include The National Council of Churches, the United States Catholic Conference, the Call to Action, Catholics for Gay Rights, Dignity, the American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors, and Therapists, the Workshop on Sexuality at Cazenovia, and the Boston Mayor's Committee on AIDS. Publications in which McNaught appears include The Michigan Catholic (in which his column "Write On" appeared), and Esplanade. McNaught's works, books and videos include A Disturbed Peace, On Being Gay, Gay Issues in the Workplace, Growing Up Gay and Lesbian, Homophobia in the Workplace and Now that I'm Out, What do I do?. Correspondents include Malcolm Boyd, Barbara Bittings, Elaine Noble, David McWhirter, Tim McFeeley, Troy Perry, Jack Baker, Lester Kirkendal, and Sol Gordon. Also, reports, pamphlets, journals, books, and ephemera on social and political aspects of sexuality, homosexuality and AIDS. Materials and final report of The Boston Project, "a year long study by the City of Boston, in conjunction with the Gay and Lesbian Community, of how we might better meet the needs of this often neglected constituency," for which McNaught served as Liaison to the gay and lesbian community.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McNaught, Brian R.; Boyd, Malcolm, 1923-.; Gittings, Barbara, 1932-.; Noble, Elaine.; McWhirter, David, 1932-.; McFeeley, Tim.; Frank, Barney, 1940-.; Perry, Troy D..; Baker, Jack.; Kirkendal, Lester.; Gordon, Sol, 1923-.; McNaught, Brian--Are You Guys Brothers?; McNaught, Brian--Disturbed peace.; McNaught, Brian--Gay issues in the workplace.; McNaught, Brian--Growing up gay and lesbian.; McNaught, Brian--Homophobia in the workplace.; McNaught, Brian--On being gay.; McNaught, Brian--Sex Camp.; Catholic Church--United States.; National Council of Churches of Christ in the United States of America.; United States Catholic Conference.; Catholics for Gay Rights.; Social Action for Dignity.; American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors, and Therapists.; Workshop on Sexuality (Cazenovia, N.Y.); Fag Rag Collective.; Mayor's Committee on AIDS (Boston, Mass.).; Marquette University.
Subjects:
Gays--Political Activity.; Gay liberation movement.; AIDS (Disease)--Prevention.; AIDS (Disease)--Study and teaching.; Gays--Religion.; Homophobia.; Gays' writings.; Gay and lesbian studies.; Gay activists.; Gays--Health and hygiene.; Gays--Societies, etc.; Gays--Religion--Societies,etc.; Work environment.; Sex--Study and teaching.; Political activists.; Gay journalists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Letters in boxes 14-16 and 24 have been RESTRICTED UNTIL 2049 by the donor.
Two folders of letters in box 24 have been RESTRICTED UNTIL 2033 by the donor.
PROVENANCE
Brian McNaught gave the first materials in this collection to the Cornell University Library in January 1995.
RELATED MATERIAL
Publications removed from collection 7590 and cataloged as individual books and serials in the Human Sexuality Collection are listed at the end of this guide under Separated Materials.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Records
Box 1 (folders 1-12), 23
Series II. Writings
Boxes 1 (folders 13-29), 2, 19, 23
Series III. Speaking Engagements and Workshops
Boxes 3-5 (folders 1-36), 23
Series IV. Catholic and Unitarian Universalist
Boxes 5 (folders 37-end), 6, 23
Series V. Boston
Boxes 6 (folders 26-30), 7
Series VI. Subject Files
Boxes 8-12, 23
Series VII. Correspondence
Boxes 13-16, 23-24
Series VIII. Support Documents
Boxes 17-20, 23
Series IX. Visual Materials and Ephemera
Boxes 21-22, 23
Series X. Audio and Video Materials
Box 22
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal Records
  This series contains the personal records of Brian McNaught from 1965 - 1998. Included in the series are diaries kept while on a hunger strike in 1974 in protest of being fired from a Catholic publication for writing about being gay; documents from his filing as a conscientious objector during the Vietnam war; address books; materials from his high school and college, and photographs.
  - Address Book, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brother Rice reunion photograph, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calendars, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendars, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conscientious Objector, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Daily diary kept during Michigan Catholic Ordeal, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs- Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Brian McNaught, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Resumes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Schools, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Personal - miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - File pertaining to McNaught's marriage in Canada to his partner, Ray Struble., 6/30/2003 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Family-related materials (Box 23, Folder 66)
- Series II. Writings
  This series contains articles and manuscripts written by Brian McNaught between the years 1969 - 1993. Included are drafts of his books On Being Gay, and A Disturbed Peace. Also included are his weekly articles "A Disturbed Peace," and "Write On!," originally written for The Michigan Catholic; and other articles written by McNaught for various publications. Other writings include an unpublished children's story Grogg the Frog; a monograph manuscript, When Irish Eyes are Gay, and a published letter to Anita Bryant: "Late Night Thoughts of a Catholic Homosexual."
  - Articles and public statements made by McNaught, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - A Disturbed Peace - Book, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - A Disturbed Peace - information about the book, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
  - A Disturbed Peace reviews, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - "A Disturbed Peace" column, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23-29)
  - "A Disturbed Peace" column, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - "A Disturbed Peace" column ideas, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - "A Disturbed Peace" column promotion, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Gay in Corporate America" article, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gay Issues in the Workplace book, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Gay Issues in the Workplace final manuscript, April 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Miscellaneous McNaught writings (includes "A Disturbed Peace"), 1970s (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Miscellaneous McNaught writings, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous McNaught writings, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
  - Miscellaneous McNaught writings, 1983-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - On Being Gay reviews, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - When Irish Eyes are Gay, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - "Write On" column, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Writings by McNaught - Contributing Editor to "Alive" Magazine, 1978-1979; May 1978; June 1978 vol. 2 no. 2; January 1979 vol. 2 no. 9 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Writings by McNaught - Essays in US Catholic, 1975-1982; "The Sad Dilemma of the Gay Catholic," Aug. 1975; "Is our Church big enough for gay Catholics," June 1980; "We are Family," Oct. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Writings by McNaught in Miscellaneous Publications, 1975-1982; "The Humanist," Sept./Oct. 1977; "In Touch," Feb./March 1975; "Learning to Live Together Through Understanding," n.d.; "Salt," Sept. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Articles by McNaught - "The Eccentric", 1969 (Box 2, Folder Oversize 1)
  - Articles by McNaught, 1970-1979; See also: entire publication in map case (Box 2, Folder Oversize 2)
  - Articles by McNaught, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder Oversize 3)
  - Bay Windows, 1984, 1987; Feb. 16-29 1984 vol. 2, no. 4; June 18-24 1987 vol. 5, no. 24 (Box 19)
  - The Blade, 1976-1977; Nov. 1976 no. 10; Dec. 1976 no. 12; Jan. 1977 no. 1; Feb. 1977 no. 2 (Box 19)
  - Contact, 1975, 1978; April 16, 1975 issue 11; June 18, 1975 issue 14; July 16, 1975 issue 15 (Box 19)
  - Esplanade, 1978; March 23, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Gazette, 1981; Dec. 3-9, 1981 vol. 2, no. 49 (Box 19)
  - GCN - Gay Community News, 1975; March 29, 1975 vol. 2, no. 40 (Box 19)
  - Gear- Ohio, 1979; January 1979 (Box 19)
  - Glad Rag, 1981; Autumn Harvest 1981 vol. 5, no.9 (Box 19)
  - High Gear, 1978; Dec. 1978 vol. 5, issue 4 (Box 19)
  - Lifestyle Boston, 1982; July 6, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Metro Gay News, 1976-1978; Aug.- Dec. 1976 vol. 1, nos. 1-5; Jan.- March 1977 vol. 2, nos. 1-3; May- Dec. 1977 vol. 2, nos. 5-12; Feb.-March 1978 vol. 3, nos. 2-3 (Box 19)
  - Metro Gay News Cummulative Index, 2005 (Box 19)
  - The Michigan Catholic, 1970-1973; Sept. 16, 1970 vol. 98; July 14, 1971 vol. 99; Dec. 6, 1972 vol. 100; Dec. 13, 1972 vol. 100; May 3, 1973 vol. CI no. 22; June 27, 1973 vol. CI no. 26 (Box 19)
  - Final Corrections on A Disturbed Peace, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Speeches and Letters to Editors by Brian McNaught, 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence regarding Combatting Heterosexism book chapter., 1994 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "Gays and Religious Conservatives as Coworkers", by Brian McNaught, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "My Friend Paul Shanley", by Brian McNaught, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous opinion pieces on ENDA, being a conscientious objector (Box 23, Folder 65)
  - Bay Windows--Boston's New Gay and Lesbian Paper, March 1983 (Box 19)
- Series III. Speaking Engagements and Workshops
  This series contains materials from workshops and lectures given by McNaught between the years 1979-2003. The bulk of the lectures were at various colleges on the subject of being gay and Catholic, and the workshops primarily deal with homophobia in the workplace. Of note are the papers from homophobia workshops at the ATT/League, a workshop series for employees of ATT designed to raise awareness about gay and lesbian issues and make ATT a more comfortable environment for gays and lesbians.
  - AIDS Training - Atlanta, May 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Allegheny College, Nov. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Association for Affirmative Action (AAAA) - Boston, Mar. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors and Therapists (AASECT) conference, Apr. 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AASECT Convention, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AASECT - George Washington University, Jul./Aug. 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Amherst University, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Association of College Unions International (ACUI), Mar. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ACUI Conference, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Atlanta, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ATT/League homophobia workshops (co-directed by McNaught and Mary Lee Tatum)
    - ATT/League, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bell Labs - Denver, May 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bell Communication, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bellcore - Background, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bell Labs, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
    - Bellcore Noon hour, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bellcore Presentation, Outline and Evaluation, Mar. 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gay Issues Workshop, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Homophobia in the Workplace" pre-workshop materials, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Homophobia in the Workplace" materials, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - League, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - League, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - League Conference, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - League Conference, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - League Feedback, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 26-29)
    - League- Speech Supplement, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - LEAGUE, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Right Wing Family Research Council Response to ATT, LEAGUE, promoting homosexuality, etc., 1994? (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Ball State, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Baltimore Gay Pride, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bloomsburg University, Feb. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Brattleboro Retreat, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Brown University, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bucknell University, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bucknell University, Sep. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Burlington, VT, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - California State Polytechnic University, Nov. 1991 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Case Western Reserve, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Castleton State College, Feb. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Castleton State College, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Caz - Sal Gordon's work, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Central Connecticut State University, Oct. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Charlotte, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Choate Rosemary Hall, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Colgate University, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Colgate University, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Colgate University, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Colorado - Conference on World Affairs, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Columbus, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cornell University, Apr. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Crane, IL, Apr. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dade County Gay Pride, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dickinson College, Feb. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Denison, 1984, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dignity - Baltimore, Oct. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dignity Convention, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dignity - Tampa, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gay Activist Alliance (GAA) - Morristown, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - GAYPAC - Gay People at Cornell, Feb. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Gay Substance Abuse conference, Oct. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Gettysburg College, Oct. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Gettysburg College, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Grand Rapids AASECT, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Grand Rapids, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Greek Conference - San Francisco, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Guelph, Jun. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hamilton College, Apr. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Harvard, Nov. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hawaii, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Hobart William Smith Colleges, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hobart William Smith Colleges, Nov. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Holy Cross College, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Homophobia conference- Washington D.C., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Independent School Health Association (ISHA) - Loomis-Chaffee School, May 1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Indiana University, Mar. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Ithaca College, Apr. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Ithaca College, Apr. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Indianapolis, Sep. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - John Snow Inc. (JSI) - Denver, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - JSI - Training, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - JSI, Jul. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Keane State College, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Kent State, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Kent State, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Maine - Gay Youth, Apr. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Maine, University of, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Maine, University of, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - March on Washington, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Marty and Mary Ann's Party, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - MATHTECH (Airlie), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Memorial Hospital, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Michigan Organization for Human Rights (MOHR), 1987; includes photos (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force - Conference, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - New England School of Alcohol Studies, Jun. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - New Mexico - includes photos, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Northern Michigan University, Mar. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oakland, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oberlin, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Oberlin, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - William Patterson College of New Jersey, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Penn State, Feb. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Planned Parenthood Indianapolis, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Planned Parenthood Manitoba, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Plymouth State College, Dec. 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rochester University, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rutgers, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sandia, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - SAR (sex education workshop), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Society for the Scientific Study of Sex (SSSS)- Regional Boston, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - St. John's, Collegeville, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - St. Jerome's Toronto, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - St. Jerome's Toronto, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - St. Lawrence University, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Strongest Link, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sunnybrook Toronto, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Syracuse (Sol Gordon), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Syracuse, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Syracuse Gay/Lesbian Awareness, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Vanderbilt, Apr. 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Vermont, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Washington AASECT, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Westmar College, Oct. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - World Congress of Sexology, Sep. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - York, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Speaking Engagements, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Promotion on College Talks, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Promotion on Workshop and Homophobia on Campus, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Various "Gay Issues in the Workplace" Workshop Evaluations, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 34-36)
  - Articles and Newsletters concerning Gay/ Catholic issues, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
  - GLBT Employee Business Resource Groups of NCR Materials (League @ NCR), 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Diversity Best Practices: Conference Call, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - WILL Global Professional Development Conference, Boston, MA, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Summit on Leading Diversity, 2001-2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - City College of San Francisco: Spring Professional Development, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Binghamton, Feb. 2-8 2001 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Broome Community College, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - City College San Francisco, Jan. 14 2002 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Clergy-Laitz Institute, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Damler-Chrysler, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Detroit Edison, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Disney, Nov. 15 2001 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - EQUAL! Conference (Lucent Technologies), 1998 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - EQUAL!/IDEAL Conference, May 18-20, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Ford, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Greek Conference, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - IBM, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Kimberly-Clark, Oct. 30 2001 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - King Avenue Methodist, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Lever Brothers, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Linkage (Summit on Leading Diversity), 2001 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Los Alamos, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Lucent-Whippany, May 14 2001 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Mass Mutual, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Merck, March 2002 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Motorola, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - North Dakota, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - San Francisco Federal Reserve, May 16 2001 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - S.C. Johnson and Sons, Inc., 1999 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Sony Music, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - St. Paul Cos., 1997 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - St. Paul, May 6-7 2002 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - UC Berkeley, USC, UCLA, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Visteon, Aug. 20 2002 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - WILL (Women In Leadership at Lucent Technologies) Conference, Mar. 30-Apr.1 2000 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Feedback on Workplace Programs, 2001-2003 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Notes on Out and Equal Conference presentation with Deb Dagit (Merck) and Kathy Marvell (Chubb) on "Sexual Health in Corporations" (Box 23, Folder 71)
  - "Understanding and Managing Gay and Transgender Issues at Chubb" (Box 23, Folder 81)
- Series IV. Catholic and Unitarian Universalist
  This series contains Brian McNaught's files that deal directly with Catholic issues and the Catholic Church. Of note are the papers and newsletters about Dignity, a national organization for gay Catholics. There are also files about the Michigan Catholic, the newspaper from which he was fired in 1974. This series also includes articles pertaining to gay Catholics and newsletters from various Catholic organizations and churches, both local and national. Also included is a file on McNaught's involvement with the Unitarian Universalist Church in Naples, FL.
  - Articles and Newsletters concerning Gay/Catholic issues (includes some Dignity), 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Brian's Article on "Gay" Bishop's letters, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "A Call to Action", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Catholics for Gay Rights, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Dignity - an organization for gay Catholics
    - Dignity, 1974-1989; Folders 44-54 labeled "Dignity" include various newsletters, correspondences and other information concerning Dignity. May contain other gay/Catholic material as well. (Box 5, Folder 44-54)